Guide to the Associated Students of Stanford University, Speakers Bureau, Audio-Visual Materials
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Associated Students of Stanford University, Speakers Bureau, audio-visual materials
1981-1996
SC0748
Associated Students of Stanford University. Speakers Bureau
Stanford University. Associated Students. Speakers Bureau.
1 Linear feet 71 audiocassettes and 4 videotapes (VHS)
Audio tapes of talks sponsored by the ASSU Speakers Bureau; presenters include Bernard Malamud, Ray Bradbury, Gore Vidal, Alexander Zinoviev, Raymond Carver, Tillie Olson, Hunter S. Thompson, Shirley Chisholm, Alex Haley, Linus Pauling, Adrienne Rich, Alonda King, Betty Friedan, Jello Biafra, Ann Richards, and Alice Walker. There are also tapes from a symposium on pornography with Andrea Dworkin, Linda Lovelace, Catherine MacKinnon, and Burton Joseph (1982); a NASA Space Shuttle talk (1982); a debate on apartheid with Bobby Seale and Stuart Pringle (1985); the Martin Luther King Jr. Birthday Celebration (1986); and the Malcolm X Birthday Celebration (1990). Collection also includes 4 miscellaneous videotapes.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
Access: A duplicate use copy of the requested tape may need to be created before listening. Please allow approximately 2 weeks.
Description of the Collection
Audio tapes of talks sponsored by the ASSU Speakers Bureau; presenters include Bernard Malamud, Ray Bradbury, Gore Vidal, Alexander Zinoviev, Raymond Carver, Tillie Olson, Hunter S. Thompson, Shirley Chisholm, Alex Haley, Linus Pauling, Adrienne Rich, Alonda King, Betty Friedan, Jello Biafra, Ann Richards, and Alice Walker. There are also tapes from a symposium on pornography with Andrea Dworkin, Linda Lovelace, Catherine MacKinnon, and Burton Joseph (1982); a NASA Space Shuttle talk (1982); a debate on apartheid with Bobby Seale and Stuart Pringle (1985); the Martin Luther King Jr. Birthday Celebration (1986); and the Malcolm X Birthday Celebration (1990). Collection also includes 4 miscellaneous videotapes.
Access Terms
Associated Students of Stanford University. Speakers Bureau; Biafra, Jello.; Bradbury, Ray, 1920-; Carver, Raymond, 1938-1988; Chisholm, Shirley, 1924-2005; Dworkin, Andrea.; Friedan, Betty.; Haley, Alex.; King, Alonda.; Lovelace, Linda.; MacKinnon, Catharine A.; Malamud, Bernard.; Olsen, Tillie; Pauling, Linus, 1901-1994.; Rich, Adrienne Cecile; Richards, Ann, 1933-2006; Seale, Bobby, 1936-; Stanford University. Associated Students.; Thompson, Hunter S.; Vidal, Gore, 1925-; Walker, Alice, 1944-; Zinoviev, Aleksandr, 1922-; Lectures and lecturing--California.; Phonotapes.
Collection Contents
- Audio-visual material
  - Group #1
    - Donald Kennedy, "Undergraduate Education at Stanford: Purpose and Prospects", Oct 28 1981; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Bernard Malamud, Kresge Auditorium, Jan 19 1982; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - John Hawkes, Kresge Auditorium, Jan 27 1982; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Ray Bradbury, "Tomorrow: Forecast of the Future" Tape 1, Kresge Auditorium, Feb 3 1982; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Writer's/Publishing Panel, Tape 1, Kresge Auditorium, Feb 17 1982; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Gore Vidal, Kresge Auditorium, Feb 23 1982; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Symposium: Andrea Dworkin, Linda Lovelace, Katherine McKinnon, Burton Joseph: "Pornography ... Does it Violate Women?" Tape 1, Dinkelspiel Auditorium, Apr 4 1982; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Symposium: Andrea Dworkin, Linda Lovelace, Katherine McKinnon, Burton Joseph: "Pornography ... Does it Violate Women?", Tape 2, Dinkelspiel Auditorium, Apr 4 1982; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Symposium: Andrea Dworkin, Linda Lovelace, Katherine McKinnon, Burton Joseph: "Pornography ... Does it Violate Women?", Tape 3, Dinkelspiel Auditorium, Apr 4 1982; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Joan Baez (film), "There But For Fortune" Kresge Auditorium, May 26 1982; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - NASA Space Shuttle Talk, Tape 1, Kresge Auditorium, Oct 17 1982; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - NASA Space Shuttle Talk, Tape 2, Kresge Auditorium, Oct 17 1982; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Alexander Zinoviev, Annenburg Auditorium, Nov 8 1982; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Alexander Zinoviev, "Discussion afterwards" Annenburg Auditorium, Nov 8 1982; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Danial Amit, Annenburg Auditorium, Nov 20 1982; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Lipset, Shuvall, Yanai, Yshai, Tape 1, Nov 29 1982; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Lipset, Shuvall, Yanai, Yshai, Tape 2, Nov 29 1982; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Group #2
    - Raymond Carver, Tape 1, Kresge Auditorium, Feb 2 1983; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Raymond Carver, Tape 2, Kresge Auditorium, Feb 2 1983; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Tobias Wolff, Annenburg Auditorium, Feb 15 1983; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Tillie Olson, Tape 1, Bishop Auditorium, Feb 23 1983; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Tillie Olson, Tape 2, Bishop Auditorium, Feb 23 1983; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Bobby Seale v. Stuart Pringle, "Apartheid Debate" Tape 1, Oct 17 1985; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Bobby Seale v. Stuart Pringle, "Apartheid Debate" Tape 2, Oct 17 1985; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - No title, Side 1 and 2., Oct 17 1985; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Dr. Hunter S. Thompson (part 1), Oct 22 1985; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Dr. Hunter S. Thompson (part 2), Oct 22 1985; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Shirley Chisholm, Jan 15 1986; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - MLK Jr. Celebration, Tape 1, Memorial Auditorium, Jan 21 1986; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - MLK Jr. Celebration, Tape 2, Memorial Auditorium, Jan 21 1986; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - MLK Jr. Celebration, Tape 3, Memorial Auditorium, Jan 21 1986; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Alex Haley, Tape 1, Dinkelspiel Auditorium, Mar 5 1986; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Alex Haley, Tape 2, Dinkelspiel Auditorium, Mar 5 1986; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Group #3
    - John Irving, Tape 1, Dinkelspiel Auditorium, Apr 21 1986; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Linus Pauling, "A Great Step Toward World Peace", Apr 29 1986; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Ted Turner, Tape 1, May 12 1986; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Ted Turner, Tape 2, May 12 1986; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Dr. Michael DeBakey, Kresge Auditorium, Jan 12 1987; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Pete DuPont, Cubberley Auditorium, Apr 10 1987; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - John Buchanan and Cal Thomas (debate), Tape 1, Kresge Auditorium, Apr 14 1987; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - John Buchanan and Cal Thomas (debate), Tape 2, Kresge Auditorium, Apr 14 1987; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Lyn Jones, Toyon, May 18 1987; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Robert Hastings, "UFOs" Tape 1, May 21 1987; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Robert Hastings, "UFOs" Tape 2, May 21 1987; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Vladimir Posner, Tape 1, Dinke1spiel Auditorium, Oct81987; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Vladimir Posner, Tape 2, Dinkelspiel Auditorium, Oct 8 1987; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Adrienne Rich, Nov 5 1987; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Jack Healey, Cubberley Auditorium, Nov 13 1987; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Jack Healey, Cubberley Auditorium, Nov 16 1987; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Group #4
    - Al Gore, Nov 24 1987; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Alonda King, Tape 1, Jan 15 1988; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Alonda King, Tape 2, Jan 15 1988; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Dr. Ron Paul, Annenburg Auditorium, Feb 11 1988; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Ben Edward Akerley, Kresge Auditorium, Feb 18 1988; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - English Language Debate, Tape 1, Mar 31 1988; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - English Language Debate, Tape 2, Mar 31 1988; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Betty Friedan, Kresge Auditorium, Apr 26 1990; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Malcolm X B-Day, Tape 1, Annenburg Auditorium, May 17 1990; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Malcolm X B-Day, Tape 2, Annenburg Auditorium, May 17 1990; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Malcolm X B-Day, Tape 3, Annenburg Auditorium, May 17 1990; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Mairead Maguire, Oct 8 1990; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Jello Biafra, Nov 5 1990; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - New Voices of Democracy Tape 1, Nov 12 1990; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - New Voices of Democracy Tape 2, Nov 12 1990; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - John H. Conway (Karel de Leeuw Memorial Lecture), May 16 1991; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Ann Richards, Nov 6 1995; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Group #5
    - Alice Walker, Memorial Auditorium, Jan 6 1996; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - PJ. O'Rourke, Memorial Auditorium, Mar 5 1996; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Iran Contra, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Lt. Col. James Bo Gritz, "U.S. Officials In the Heroin Trade", 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Untitled, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Videotapes
    - Victor Morales, U.S. Senate Race, 1996; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
    - Safe Speech, Free Speech, and the University, 1991 Apr 10; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
    - Hypnosis, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
    - Computer Voting, News Channel 5, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
      Aronson, Sandy